In the Kremlin, no one can hear you scheme
The Death of Stalin is a comedy, drama, history
film directed by Armando Iannucci.
When dictator Joseph Stalin dies, his parasitic cronies square off in a
frantic power struggle to become the next Soviet leader.
As they bumble, brawl and back-stab their way to the top, the
question remains — just who is running the government?
Nikita Khrushchev, played by Steve Buscemi.
Lavrenti Beria, played by Simon Russell Beale.
Georgy Malenkov, played by Jeffrey Tambor.
Field Marshal Zhukov, played by Jason Isaacs.
Vyacheslav Molotov, played by Michael Palin.
Vasily Stalin, played by Rupert Friend.
The Death of Stalin is a 2017 political satire black comedy film directed by Armando Iannucci
and written by Iannucci, David Schneider and Ian Martin with Peter Fellows.
Based on the French graphic novel La Mort de Staline (2010–2012), the film depicts the internal social and political power
struggle among the members of the Soviet Politburo following the death of leader Joseph Stalin in 1953.
The French-British-Belgian co-production stars an ensemble cast that includes Steve Buscemi, Simon Russell Beale, Paddy Considine, Rupert Friend, Jason
Isaacs, Olga Kurylenko, Michael Palin, Andrea Riseborough, Dermot Crowley, Paul Chahidi, Adrian McLoughlin, Paul Whitehouse, and Jeffrey Tambor.
The film premiered on 8 September 2017 at the
Toronto International Film Festival.
It was released theatrically in the United Kingdom by Entertainment One Films on 20 October 2017, in France
by Gaumont on 4 April 2018, and in Belgium by September Film Distribution on 18 April 2018.
It received critical acclaim and various accolades, including nominations for two British Academy Film Awards, one of
which was for Outstanding British Film, and 13 British Independent Film Awards, four of which it won.
There was fierce opposition to the film in Russia, where it was seen as "anti-Russian propaganda", and it was
banned there, as well as in Kyrgyzstan, for allegedly mocking the Soviet Union and its past.
The film explores themes of chaos, dictator, socialism, dark comedy, satire.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.